RG 004:021, Canaan Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Canaan Probate Court records
1844-1927
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Canaan District)
16.25 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1847-1927; Probate files, 1844-1912.
RG004_021
1914-003 and 2011-036
Historical Note
Canaan, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1739
The Canaan Probate District was constituted June 6, 1846, from the Sharon Probate District. It served the municipalities of Canaan and North Canaan. The Canaan Probate District merged with the Cornwall, Norfolk, Salisbury, and Sharon Probate Districts on January 1, 2007 to create the Northwest Corner Probate District. The Northwest Corner Probate District merged with the Harwinton, Litchfield, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
Town of Canaan, Probate District chronology:
October 1739 - October 1742, Hartford District
October 1742 - October 1755, Litchfield District
October 1755 - June 5, 1846, Sharon District
June 6, 1846 - December 31, 2006, Canaan District
January 1, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Northwest Corner District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-16, 1847-1927. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 16.
Probate files, 1844-1912. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1844-1912 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 16.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1914-003 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Canaan; Probate records -- Connecticut -- North Canaan
Places:
Canaan (Conn.); North Canaan (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-036, Record books, 1838-1941, are be stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12-13, 15, 1847-1919; probate files 1844-1912 (Accession 1914-003); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1914-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 3, 1914 (1844-1912); March 5, 1928 (1868-1912). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-036 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 28, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1847-1927; 9 cubic feet; 2011-036
  - Records, 1847-1860 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1858-1871 (Volume 2)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Order book, 1858-1880 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1871-1884 (Volume 4)
  - Order book, 1879-1892 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1881-1891 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1881-1841 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1891-1896 (Volume 8)
  - Order book, 1892-1902 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1896-1902 (Volume 10)
  - Order book, 1901-1911 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1902-1907 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1908-1915 (Volume 13)
  - Order book, 1911-1919 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1914-1923 (Volume 15)
  - Order book, 1919-1927 (Volume 16)
- Probate files, 1844-1912; 7.25 cubic feet; 1914-003
  - Abbott - Austell (Drawer 1)
  - Averill - Beckley (Drawer 2)
  - Bedell - Bettis (Drawer 3)
  - Bigelow - Brown (Drawer 4)
  - Bruey - Capron (Box 5)
  - Carroll - Cleveland (Box 6)
  - Cosgswell - Dean, H. (Box 7)
  - Dean, J. - Douglas (Box 8)
  - Dresser - Folker (Box 9)
  - Foote - Gingel (Box 10)
  - Girard - Hayward (Box 11)
  - Henry - Hurlburt, J. (Drawer 12)
  - Hurlburt, K. - Landon (Drawer 13)
  - Lane - Maxim (Drawer 14)
  - McAllister - Newton (Drawer 15)
  - Nichols - Porter (Box 16)
  - Post - Rood (Box 17)
  - Root - Smith (Box 18)
  - Sparks - Tierney (Box 19)
  - Tobey - Watson, G. (Box 20)
  - Watson, H. - Wooster (Box 21)
  - Wright - Z; Miscellaneous (Box 22)
- Inventory control book, 1844-1912; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1914-003
  Also known as the Godard Digest